Curriculum Vitae Sercan Özen

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Sercan Özen



- Yenişehir Mh Berkay Sk 1/B Pendik/ Istanbul / TURKEY
- +90 546 514 33 37
- sercangsu@gmail.com
- www.sercanozen.com/blog Github.com/sercan5534

Youtube.com/#GioCodeHouse

Skype sercan5534

Sex M | Year of birth 1987 | Nationality Turkish

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Skillful computer engineer with 6+ years of experience in software development in JavaScript, Java, Swift, HTML and CSS. Passionate about learning, designing, developing and solving things. Experience in international projects, currently working in cyber-security. Looking for international career opportunities in short future.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Since 12/2017

Front-End Engineer @ Gittigidiyor.com (Ebay)

Developing new features and bug fixing. Refactoring and improving the performance of code base with the best practice of JavaScript.

- HTML, JS (with jQuery) & Css development of new features
- Development of the functional tests with Robot Framework
- Performance tuning using Lighthouse
- Integration new design system to the web site

07/2015 - 12/2017

Software Design Engineer @ NETA\$

Determining operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition, requirements, solution development, and proposed solutions. Documenting and demonstrating solutions. Preparing and installing solutions by determining and designing system specifications, standards, and programming. Improving operations by conducting systems analysis; recommending changes in policies and procedures. Develops software solutions by studying information needs; conferring with users; studying systems flow, data usage, and work processes; investigating problem areas; following the software development lifecycle.

- Design & code implementation of micro services with Jersey, Hibernate, Spring Framework
- Design & development of responsive client websites with Angular-js & CSS3
- Design & development of mobile applications in iOS with swift 2
- Database design and PostgreSQL implementation
- Experience with task manager and package manager systems
- Test behavior development experience
- Web security experience in SQL Injection, XSS
- Experience in Webrtc, Turn/StunServer and Cryptology

04/2011 - 07/2015

Senior Front-End Developer @ Sword-IT

Teamleader, responsible of developping processes. UX consultancy for business customers.

- Design and development of html, css and javascript based web sites.
- Facebook applications of .Net and php based web sites.
- Design and development of Wordpress themes and plugins.
- Development of web applications in Asp.Net MVC 4.
- Design and development of responsive web sites.

10/2009 - 04/2011

Designer and Content Manager @ Council of Shopping Centers and Investors Association (AMPD)

Content & design management of the company webpage. Designing newsletters, news, flyers etc.

Curriculum Vitae Sercan Özen

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

BSc. in Computer Engineering @ Galatasaray University, Istanbul

Software Dev, Databases, Networks, Robotics, Op Systems, Artificial Int, Comp Architecture

PROJECT PORTFOLIO

Buhane.com

It's a personal project which connect landlord and tenant in platform. In this project, we use last technologies for front-end and back-end services.

- Coding front-end using React JS library supported Redux.
- Coding of various microservices (used Spring Cloud)
- Manage front-end pipeline

Applied technologies: React JS, Redux, CSS3, HTML5, Java, Spring Boot & Spring Cloud, Webpack, Babel, Nodejs (express framework)

Nova W-Spy

W-Spy is an automatic web security scanner tool in Nova Security Product Family. It aims to find vulnerabilities in web sites or web application using microservice architecture with high performance and flexibility.

- Coding of various microservices and their REST APIs in Spring framework
- Single interface design for complete microservices set and its development in angular-js
- Creation of Jenkins CI pipelines and error feedback tools.
- Unit test development for front-end and back-end
- Functional test design for microservices

Applied technologies: Angular-js, Js, CSS3, HTML5, Java, Hibernate, Jersey, Spring, Jasmine, jUnit, Mockito

Nova MSP

MSP (Media Security Platform) is a mobile application providing secure communication over WebRTC platform. It's a member of Nova Security Product Family.

- Application architecture, design and development of user UI
- Development of Webrtc communication system
- Applied technologies: Swift 2, Xcode

ZIMS

ZIMS (Zoo Information Management System) is a global real-time information management software with over 10K+ active users.

- Development, testing and module management of the software
- Applied technologies: Js & Ext Js libraries, html, css, C#, .Net.

Ainsworth.com

Web page of the Canadian energy company Ainsworth

 UI/UX Design, development in html, Js, css ve C#, .Net. Admin interface modules development in Ext Js

Mantolama.co

Exterior thermal sheathing and insulation works website. SMS service and client upload service development.

TeamTaskTracker

• UI/UX and development in html, Js, css, C#,.Net. Admin interface modules development in Ext Js UI/UX and development html, Js, css, C#,.Net. Admin interface modules development in Ext Js

Formdakal.com

Wordpress custom theme creation for healthy nutrition web page

Konforlubebekler.com diyetimibozdum.com

Wordpress custom theme creation for healthy nutrition web page. Responsive web design and development for nutrition company. Js, Html, Css, MVC/.Net, EF 6,MsSQL

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Football lover, traveller and chef of own house.